<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GIT on A programmers notebook</title>
    <link>http://pi14tech.com/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GIT on A programmers notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://pi14tech.com/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>http://pi14tech.com/git/cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pi14tech.com/git/cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>Table 1. Configuration CommandUsageCommandUsage Revert Changes git reset HEAD~Discard local commit. Changes will remain in localgit revert 8f937c6 -m 1Git revert a merged commit .
git reset HEAD~Discard local commit. Changes will remain in localgit revert 8f937c6 -m 1 git revert 8f937c6 -m 2Git revert a merged commit </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Branch - rename</title>
      <link>http://pi14tech.com/git/rename-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pi14tech.com/git/rename-branch/</guid>
      <description>GIT Rename branchIt&amp;#8217;s quite common we start using a temporary name for a feature branch we are working on, and we have to rename the branch to something more meaningful as our work progresses.
In case, the git branch is still in local and has not been pushed to remote, below command can be used to rename the branch locally
Rename branch locally git branch -m old_branch new_branch
In case, the branch was pushed to remote and you want to rename the remote branch as well</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherry pick</title>
      <link>http://pi14tech.com/git/git-cherry-pick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pi14tech.com/git/git-cherry-pick/</guid>
      <description>GIT cherry pickCherry picking in git means to choose a commit from one branch and apply it onto another. This is in contrast with other ways such as merge and rebase which normally applies many commits onto a another branch.
How to cherry pick?
Make sure you are on the branch you want apply the commit to.
`git checkout master`Cherry pick a specific commit feature you need from list of commits</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merge</title>
      <link>http://pi14tech.com/git/git-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pi14tech.com/git/git-merge/</guid>
      <description>GIT MergeMerge bugfix/feature onto master/devSay your bug fix branch is called bugfix and you want to merge it into master:
git checkout master
git merge --squash bugfix
git commit
This will take all the commits from the bugfix branch, squash them into 1 commit and then merge it with your master branch.
In case you think there are possible merge conflicts that can occur between master and bugfix but you know that bugfix branch has the correct changes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revert - Merged Commit</title>
      <link>http://pi14tech.com/git/git-revert-merged-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pi14tech.com/git/git-revert-merged-commit/</guid>
      <description>GIT revert merged commitGit revert a merged commit
The -m option specifies the parent number. This is because a merge commit has more than one parent, and Git does not know automatically which parent was the mainline, and which parent was the branch you want to un-merge.
When you view a merge commit in the output of git log, you will see its parents listed on the line that begins with Merge:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tag - create</title>
      <link>http://pi14tech.com/git/create-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pi14tech.com/git/create-tag/</guid>
      <description>GIT Create TagTo create a tag on your current branch, run this:
git tag &amp;lt;tagname&amp;gt;
This will create a local tag with the current state of the branch you are on. When pushing to your remote repo, tags are NOT included by default. You will need to explicitly say that you want to push your tags to your remote repo:
git push origin —tags
Note: This command will push all the tags in your local machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tag - delete</title>
      <link>http://pi14tech.com/git/delete-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pi14tech.com/git/delete-tag/</guid>
      <description>GIT Delete Local/Remote TagIts quite common during a release process or a tag process, you will need to retag a specific version or remove a tag that was already pushed to remote branch.
To remove a tag if it has been pushed to remote repository
git push --delete origin tagname
If you also need to delete the local tag, use:
git tag --delete tagname
Dissecting what happened abovePushing a branch, tag, or other ref to a remote repository involves specifying &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>